questions = [
  {
    "course_id": "3",
    "question_text": "A group of market women sell at least one of yam, plantain and maize. 12 of them sell maize, 10 sell yam and 14 sell plantain. 5 sell plantain and maize, 4 sell yam and maize, 2 sell yam and plantain only while 3 sell all the three items. How many women are in the group?",
    "option_a": "25",
    "option_b": "19",
    "option_c": "18",
    "option_d": "17",
    "correct_option": "B"
  },
  {
    "course_id": "3",
    "question_text": "If log 10 to base 8 = X, evaluate log 5 to base 8 in terms of X.",
    "option_a": "\\(\\frac{1}{2}X\\)",
    "option_b": "X-\\(\\frac{1}{4}\\)",
    "option_c": "X-\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)",
    "option_d": "X-\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",
    "correct_option": "C"
  },
  {
    "course_id": "3",
    "question_text": "Find the value of X if \\(\\frac{\\sqrt{2}}{x+\\sqrt{2}}=\\frac{1}{x-\\sqrt{2}}\\)",
    "option_a": "3√2+4",
    "option_b": "3√2-4",
    "option_c": "3-2√2",
    "option_d": "4+2√2",
    "correct_option": "D"
  },
  {
    "course_id": "3",
    "question_text": "If \\(\\frac{(a^2 b^{-3}c)^{\\frac{3}{4}}}{a^{-1}b^{4}c^{5}}=a^{p} b^{q} c^{r}\\) What is the value of p+2q?",
    "option_a": "(5/2)",
    "option_b": "-(5/4)",
    "option_c": "-(25/4)",
    "option_d": "-10",
    "correct_option": "D"
  },
  {
    "course_id": "3",
    "question_text": "A trader bought 100 oranges at 5 for N1.20, 20 oranges got spoilt and the remaining were sold at 4 for N1.50. Find the percentage gain or loss.",
    "option_a": "30% gain",
    "option_b": "25% gain",
    "option_c": "30% loss",
    "option_d": "25% loss",
    "correct_option": "B"
  },
  {
    "course_id": "3",
    "question_text": "What is the answer when 2434\\(_6\\) is divided by 42\\(_6\\)?",
    "option_a": "236",
    "option_b": "356",
    "option_c": "526",
    "option_d": "556",
    "correct_option": "A"
  },
  {
    "course_id": "3",
    "question_text": "If 2\\(_9\\) x (Y3)\\(_9\\) = 3\\(_5\\) x (Y3)\\(_5\\), find the value of Y.",
    "option_a": "4",
    "option_b": "3",
    "option_c": "2",
    "option_d": "1",
    "correct_option": "C"
  },
  {
    "course_id": "3",
    "question_text": "Simplify \\(\\sqrt{\\frac{(0.0023 \\times 750)}{(0.00345 \\times 1.25)}}\\)",
    "option_a": "15",
    "option_b": "20",
    "option_c": "40",
    "option_d": "75",
    "correct_option": "A"
  },
  {
    "course_id": "3",
    "question_text": "If \\(m*n = (\\frac{m}{n} - \\frac{n}{m})\\) for m, n belong to R, evaluate -3*4",
    "option_a": "\\(\\frac{-25}{12}\\)",
    "option_b": "\\(\\frac{-7}{12}\\)",
    "option_c": "\\(\\frac{7}{12}\\)",
    "option_d": "\\(\\frac{25}{12}\\)",
    "correct_option": "B"
  },
  {
    "course_id": "3",
    "question_text": "The sum of two numbers is twice their difference. If the difference of the numbers is P, find the larger of the two numbers",
    "option_a": "p/2",
    "option_b": "3p/2",
    "option_c": "5p/2",
    "option_d": "3p",
    "correct_option": "B"
  },
  {
    "course_id": "3",
    "question_text": "A binary operation * is defined by a*b = ab+a+b for any real number a and b. if the identity element is zero, find the inverse of 2 under this operation.",
    "option_a": "2/3",
    "option_b": "1/2",
    "option_c": "-1/2",
    "option_d": "-2/3",
    "correct_option": "D"
  },
  {
    "course_id": "3",
    "question_text": "Factorize completely \\(x^{2} + 2xy + y^{2} + 3x + 3y - 18\\).",
    "option_a": "(x+y+6)(x+y-3)",
    "option_b": "(x-y-6)(x-y+3)",
    "option_c": "(x-y+6)(x-y-3)",
    "option_d": "(x+y-6)(x+y+3)",
    "correct_option": "A"
  },
  {
    "course_id": "3",
    "question_text": "Tope bought X oranges at N5.00 each and some mangoes at N4.00 each. if she bought twice as many mangoes as oranges and spent at least N65.00 and at most N130.00, find the range of values of X.",
    "option_a": "4≤X≤5",
    "option_b": "5≤X≤8",
    "option_c": "5≤X≤10",
    "option_d": "8≤X≤10",
    "correct_option": "B"
  },
  {
    "course_id": "3",
    "question_text": "Three consecutive positive integers k, l and m are such that l\\(^2\\) = 3(k+m). Find the value of m.",
    "option_a": "4",
    "option_b": "5",
    "option_c": "6",
    "option_d": "7",
    "correct_option": "C"
  },
  {
    "course_id": "3",
    "question_text": "Express \\(\\frac{1}{x^{3}-1}\\) in partial fractions",
    "option_a": "\\(\\frac{1}{3}(\\frac{1}{x - 1} - \\frac{(x + 2)}{x^{2} + x + 1})\\)",
    "option_b": "\\(\\frac{1}{3}(\\frac{1}{x - 1} - \\frac{x - 2}{x^{2} + x + 1})\\)",
    "option_c": "\\(\\frac{1}{3}(\\frac{1}{x - 1} - \\frac{(x - 2)}{x^{2} + x + 1})\\)",
    "option_d": "\\(\\frac{1}{3}(\\frac{1}{x - 1} - \\frac{(x - 1)}{x^{2} - x - 1})\\)",
    "correct_option": "A"
  }
]



# questions = [
#      {
#         'course_id': 10,
#         'question_text': "",
#         'option_a': "",
#         'option_b': "",
#         'option_c': "",
#         'option_d': "",
#         'correct_option': "",
#     },
# ]


# from webapp.cbt import questions
# from webapp.models import Course, PastQuestionsObj

# for question_data in questions:
#     try:
#         course = Course.objects.get(id=question_data['course_id'])
#         PastQuestionsObj.objects.create(
#             course=course,
#             question_text=question_data['question_text'],
#             option_a=question_data['option_a'],
#             option_b=question_data['option_b'],
#             option_c=question_data['option_c'],
#             option_d=question_data['option_d'],
#             correct_option=question_data['correct_option']
#         )
#         print(f"Added question: {question_data['question_text']}")
#     except Course.DoesNotExist:
#         print(f"Course with ID {question_data['course_id']} does not exist.")
#     except Exception as e:
#         print(f"An error occurred: {e}")


